S1701 POVERTY STATUS IN THE PAST 12 MONTHS 2009-2013 American Community Survey 5-Year Estimates

Although the American Community Survey (ACS) produces population, demographic and housing unit estimates, it is the Census Bureau's Population Estimates Program that produces and disseminates the official estimates of the population for the nation, states, counties, cities and towns and estimates of housing units for states and counties.

Supporting documentation on code lists, subject definitions, data accuracy, and statistical testing can be found on the American Community Survey website in the Data and Documentation section.

Sample size and data quality measures (including coverage rates, allocation rates, and response rates) can be found on the American Community Survey website in the Methodology section.

Subject	Barre town, Washington County, Vermont							
	Total		Below poverty level		Percent below poverty level			
	Estimate	Margin of Error	Estimate	Margin of Error	Estimate	Margin of Error		
Population for whom poverty status is determined	7,918	+/-22	266	+/-124	3.4%	+/-1.6		
AGE								
Under 18 years	1,674	+/-165	77	+/-75	4.6%	+/-4.4		
Related children under 18 years	1,674	+/-165	77	+/-75	4.6%	+/-4.4		
18 to 64 years	4,936	+/-172	150	+/-79	3.0%	+/-1.6		
65 years and over	1,308	+/-159	39	+/-32	3.0%	+/-2.4		
SEX								
Male	4,112	+/-186	113	+/-70	2.7%	+/-1.7		
Female	3,806	+/-188	153	+/-85	4.0%	+/-2.2		
RACE AND HISPANIC OR LATINO ORIGIN								
One race	7,863	+/-53	243	+/-116	3.1%	+/-1.5		
White	7,741	+/-106	243	+/-116	3.1%	+/-1.5		
Black or African American	0	+/-13	0	+/-13	-	**		
American Indian and Alaska Native	0	+/-13	0	+/-13	-	**		
Asian	122	+/-111	0	+/-13	0.0%	+/-15.1		
Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander	0	+/-13	0	+/-13	-	**		
Some other race	0	+/-13	0	+/-13	-	**		
Two or more races	55	+/-43	23	+/-35	41.8%	+/-46.7		
Hispanic or Latino origin (of any race)	172	+/-120	0	+/-13	0.0%	+/-11.0		
White alone, not Hispanic or Latino	7,569	+/-160	243	+/-116	3.2%	+/-1.5		
EDUCATIONAL ATTAINMENT								
Population 25 years and over	5,701	+/-219	140	+/-61	2.5%	+/-1.1		
Less than high school graduate	345	+/-128	29	+/-27	8.4%	+/-7.9		
High school graduate (includes equivalency)	2,575	+/-330	87	+/-51	3.4%	+/-2.0		
Some college, associate's degree	1,601	+/-219	24	+/-24	1.5%	+/-1.5		
Bachelor's degree or higher	1,180	+/-222	0	+/-13	0.0%	+/-1.7		
EMPLOYMENT STATUS								
Civilian labor force 16 years and over	4,596	+/-230	79	+/-59	1.7%	+/-1.3		
Employed	4,454	+/-238	55	+/-51	1.2%	+/-1.2		
Male	2,282	+/-183	43	+/-48	1.9%	+/-2.1		
Female	2,172	+/-184	12	+/-16	0.6%	+/-0.7		
Unemployed	142	+/-76	24	+/-26	16.9%	+/-15.4		
Male	92	+/-57	10	+/-15	10.9%	+/-16.1		
Female	50	+/-46	14	+/-21	28.0%	+/-39.6		
WORK EXPERIENCE								
Population 16 years and over	6,549	+/-158	201	+/-89	3.1%	+/-1.4		

1 of 3 12/12/2014 08:57 AM

	Barre town, Washington County, Vermont							
	Total		Below poverty level		Percent below poverty level			
Subject	Estimate	Margin of Error	Estimate	Margin of Error	Estimate	Margin of Error		
Worked full-time, year-round in the past 12 months	3,160	+/-216	18	+/-19	0.6%	+/-0.6		
Worked part-time or part-year in the past 12 months	1,742	+/-222	42	+/-49	2.4%	+/-2.7		
Did not work	1,647	+/-204	141	+/-63	8.6%	+/-3.7		
All Individuals below:								
50 percent of poverty level	203	+/-116	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
125 percent of poverty level	467	+/-199	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
150 percent of poverty level	623	+/-229	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
185 percent of poverty level	1,144	+/-326	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
200 percent of poverty level	1,237	+/-344	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
Unrelated individuals for whom poverty status is determined	1,285	+/-215	126	+/-69	9.8%	+/-4.9		
Male	531	+/-140	67	+/-51	12.6%	+/-9.2		
Female	754	+/-123	59	+/-45	7.8%	+/-5.7		
Mean income deficit for unrelated individuals (dollars)	7,224	+/-2,120	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		
Worked full-time, year-round in the past 12 months	568	+/-169	4	+/-8	0.7%	+/-1.4		
Worked less than full-time, year-round in the past 12 months	207	+/-95	27	+/-44	13.0%	+/-20.0		
Did not work	510	+/-123	95	+/-54	18.6%	+/-9.4		
PERCENT IMPUTED								
Poverty status for individuals	22.9%	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)	(X)		

Source: U.S. Census Bureau, 2009-2013 5-Year American Community Survey

Explanation of Symbols:

An *** entry in the margin of error column indicates that either no sample observations or too few sample observations were available to compute a standard error and thus the margin of error. A statistical test is not appropriate.

An '-' entry in the estimate column indicates that either no sample observations or too few sample observations were available to compute an estimate, or a ratio of medians cannot be calculated because one or both of the median estimates falls in the lowest interval or upper interval of an open-ended distribution.

An $\dot{\cdot}$ following a median estimate means the median falls in the lowest interval of an open-ended distribution.

An '+' following a median estimate means the median falls in the upper interval of an open-ended distribution.

An '***' entry in the margin of error column indicates that the median falls in the lowest interval or upper interval of an open-ended distribution. A statistical test is not appropriate.

An '****** entry in the margin of error column indicates that the estimate is controlled. A statistical test for sampling variability is not appropriate. An 'N' entry in the estimate and margin of error columns indicates that data for this geographic area cannot be displayed because the number of sample cases is too small.

An '(X)' means that the estimate is not applicable or not available.

Data are based on a sample and are subject to sampling variability. The degree of uncertainty for an estimate arising from sampling variability is represented through the use of a margin of error. The value shown here is the 90 percent margin of error. The margin of error can be interpreted roughly as providing a 90 percent probability that the interval defined by the estimate minus the margin of error and the estimate plus the margin of error (the lower and upper confidence bounds) contains the true value. In addition to sampling variability, the ACS estimates are subject to nonsampling error (for a discussion of nonsampling variability, see Accuracy of the Data). The effect of nonsampling error is not represented in these tables.

While the 2009-2013 American Community Survey (ACS) data generally reflect the February 2013 Office of Management and Budget (OMB) definitions of metropolitan and micropolitan statistical areas; in certain instances the names, codes, and boundaries of the principal cities shown in ACS tables may differ from the OMB definitions due to differences in the effective dates of the geographic entities.

Estimates of urban and rural population, housing units, and characteristics reflect boundaries of urban areas defined based on Census 2010 data. As a result, data for urban and rural areas from the ACS do not necessarily reflect the results of ongoing urbanization.

2 of 3 12/12/2014 08:57 AM

Source: U.S. Census Bureau | American FactFinder

3 of 3 12/12/2014 08:57 AM